Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم الإدارة، شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
It's you.
أنت هو.
The sword's edge is chillingly sharp,
حافة السيف حادة بشكل مخيف،
and it leaves its sheath silently.
ويخرج من غمده بصمت.
It is indeed a fine sword.
إنه سيف رائع بالفعل.
It perfectly suits a hero like Your Lordship.
إنه يناسب تمامًا بطلًا مثل صاحب السمو.
♪Loneliness, how do I cross it? Whom have I ever failed?♪
♪الوحدة، كيف أتجاوزها؟ من خذلتُه يوماً؟♪
You are quite forward.
أنت صريح جداً.
Your Lordship's renown
شهرة سيادتكم
is known to everyone.
معروف للجميع.
Where the sword points,
حيث يشير السيف،
all enemies retreat.
جميع الأعداء يتراجعون.
Furthermore, you cherish beauty and understand intentions,
علاوة على ذلك، أنت تُقدّر الجمال وتفهم النوايا،
a gentleman as pure as jade.
رجل نبيل نقي كاليشم.
It is my honor
إنه لشرف لي
to serve Your Lordship.
لخدمة سيادتكم.
♪Sorrow, counting it carefully, who stayed by my side through hardship?♪
♪يا حزني، أحصيه بدقة، من بقي بجانبي في الشدائد؟♪
♪There will eventually be a pure land where all karmic burden is cast away♪
♪ستكون هناك في النهاية أرض طاهرة حيث يتم التخلص من كل عبء كارمي♪
♪Not until worldly splendor fades,♪
♪لن يحدث ذلك إلا بعد أن يزول بريق الدنيا،♪
♪Can one understand what cuts to the bone.♪
هل يستطيع المرء أن يفهم ما يقطع العظم؟
You want to serve me,
تريد أن تخدمني،
then I must see
إذن يجب أن أرى
what abilities you possess.
ما هي القدرات التي تمتلكها؟
♪Where blossoms fall, I'm glad the fragrance in our hearts stays the same.♪
حيثما تتساقط الأزهار، يسعدني أن يبقى العطر في قلوبنا كما هو.
♪Youth slips away,♪
♪الشباب يتلاشى،♪
♪Just to wait for your once-in-a-thousand-years glance.♪
♪فقط لننتظر نظرتك التي لا تتكرر إلا مرة كل ألف عام.♪
Last time, with the Moonlit Neon Dress Dance,
في المرة الماضية، مع رقصة فستان النيون تحت ضوء القمر،
I was not fully satisfied.
لم أكن راضياً تماماً.
Since you wish to serve me today,
بما أنك ترغب في خدمتي اليوم،
then dance until I've had my fill.
ثم أرقص حتى أشبع رغبتي.
♪Time rests upon the strings, waiting for someone to brew a pot of tea.♪
♪يستقر الزمن على الأوتار، منتظراً من يقوم بتحضير إبريق شاي.♪
Please forgive me, Your Lordship.
أرجو أن تسامحني يا صاحب السمو.
My skills have been neglected for a long time.
لقد تم إهمال مهاراتي لفترة طويلة.
I'm afraid it will be difficult to obey today.
أخشى أن يكون من الصعب الامتثال اليوم.
I will surely practice diligently another day
سأتدرب بجد في يوم آخر بالتأكيد
to please Your Lordship.
لإرضاء سيادتكم.
(So, these eyes)
(إذن، هاتان العينان)
(can be so deceitful.)
(يمكن أن يكون خادعاً للغاية.)
=The Architect=
=المهندس المعماري=
=Episode 5= (I am Shen Changning. I am not dead.)
=الحلقة 5= (أنا شين تشانغنينغ. أنا لست ميتاً.)
For a concubine to enter the residence, the Madam must give her consent.
لكي تدخل إحدى الجواري إلى المسكن، يجب على السيدة أن تعطي موافقتها.
This is the rule.
هذه هي القاعدة.
Moreover, you were raised in the palace since childhood,
علاوة على ذلك، فقد نشأت في القصر منذ طفولتك،
your status is extremely noble.
مكانتك نبيلة للغاية.
How can the Governor act on his own authority?
كيف يمكن للمحافظ أن يتصرف بناءً على سلطته الخاصة؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
they simply do not regard you
إنهم ببساطة لا يكترثون بك
as important at all!
لا يقل أهمية عن أي شيء آخر!
He is doing this on purpose.
إنه يفعل ذلك عن قصد.
I thought the person in his heart was dead,
ظننت أن الشخص الذي في قلبه قد مات.
and no other woman could ever catch his eye.
ولم تستطع أي امرأة أخرى أن تلفت انتباهه.
I never thought
لم أكن أتخيل ذلك أبداً
another dancer, extremely similar
راقصة أخرى، تشبهها إلى حد كبير
to Shen Changning would appear.
سيظهر شين تشانغنينغ.
Xi Yan, is it?
شي يان، أليس كذلك؟
Don't think that just because you
لا تظن أن مجرد كونك
bear a slight resemblance to her,
يشبهها قليلاً،
and the Governor glances at you a few times,
ويلقي الحاكم نظرة خاطفة عليك عدة مرات،
that I wouldn't dare touch you.
أنني لن أجرؤ على لمسك.
Qin Feng!
تشين فنغ!
What is going on here?
ما الذي يحدث هنا؟
The serving girls who were dismissed the day before yesterday.
الخادمات اللواتي تم تسريحهن قبل يومين.
Weren't they supposed to have been sent away?
ألم يكن من المفترض أن يتم إبعادهم؟
The rule of the Governor's Residence is
قواعد مقر إقامة الحاكم هي
to be carried out horizontally,
يتم تنفيذه أفقياً،
which is also called dismissal.
وهو ما يسمى أيضاً بالفصل من العمل.
Lowly servants like you
أيها الخدم الحقيرون أمثالكم
are like ants.
يشبهون النمل.
How easily you can be killed.
كم هو سهل أن تُقتل.
(He is just a dagger wielded by the Emperor.)
(إنه مجرد خنجر يحمله الإمبراطور.)
(His hands are stained with blood and the souls of the wronged.)
(يداه ملطختان بالدماء وأرواح المظلومين.)
(How could I possibly rely on such a man?)
(كيف لي أن أعتمد على رجل كهذا؟)
(His so-called affection)
(ما يسمى بمودته)
(is merely a chess piece on my path to revenge.)
(إنها مجرد قطعة شطرنج في طريقي للانتقام.)
Xi Yan, don't think that just because you received
شي يان، لا تظني أن مجرد حصولك على
a few approving glances from the Governor
نظرات موافقة قليلة من الحاكم
that you can become arrogant with favor.
أنك قد تصبح متغطرسًا بسبب النعم.
If he ceases to shield you,
إذا توقف عن حمايتك،
as glorious as you are today,
بمجدك الذي أنت عليه اليوم،
tomorrow
غداً
you will die just as miserably.
ستموت بنفس القدر من البؤس.
You are wrong.
أنت مخطئ.
I am no man's plaything.
لستُ لعبة في يد أحد.
My fate
مصيري
is only in my own hands.
الأمر بيدي وحدي.
Life or death
الحياة أو الموت
will not be dictated by anyone else.
لن يتم إملاء أي شيء من قبل أي شخص آخر.
Your Lordship, all the serving girls in the backyard have left.
يا صاحب السمو، لقد غادرت جميع الخادمات في الفناء الخلفي.
I have informed them that this was Xi Yan's intention.
لقد أبلغتهم أن هذه كانت نية شي يان.
They all resent Xi Yan for vying for favor and being jealous.
جميعهم يشعرون بالاستياء من شي يان بسبب سعيها للحصول على امتيازات وشعورها بالغيرة.
No one suspected
لم يشتبه أحد
that their identity as spies had already been exposed.
أن هويتهم كجواسيس قد تم كشفها بالفعل.
They even wished to obtain your favor.
بل إنهم تمنوا الحصول على رضاك.
However, Xi Yan's background is special.
لكن خلفية شي يان مميزة.
Why does Your Lordship still keep her in the Residence?
لماذا لا يزال سيادتكم يبقونها في مقر الإقامة؟
Qin Feng.
تشين فنغ.
Do you still remember
هل ما زلت تتذكر؟
our days in the gladiator arena?
أيامنا في حلبة المصارعة؟
Back then,
في ذلك الوقت،
we lived worse than pigs and dogs in the arena,
لقد عشنا حياة أسوأ من حياة الخنازير والكلاب في الحلبة،
yet we still had to fight wild beasts.
ومع ذلك، كان علينا أن نقاتل الوحوش البرية.
Only by defeating the wild beasts
لا سبيل إلى ذلك إلا بهزيمة الوحوش البرية
could we qualify to fight people.
هل يمكننا أن نكون مؤهلين لمحاربة الناس؟
A slight mistake
خطأ طفيف
would lead to certain death.
سيؤدي ذلك إلى الموت المحقق.
In those days,
في تلك الأيام،
if Your Lordship hadn't led me
لولا أن هديتني يا صاحب السمو
and fiercely carved out a path of blood,
وشقّ بعنف طريقاً من الدماء،
I'm afraid
أخشى
I would have died long ago.
لكنت مت منذ زمن بعيد.
Your Lordship means...
يا صاحب السمو، هذا يعني...
There were hidden schemes and power struggles in the inner courtyard
كانت هناك مؤامرات خفية وصراعات على السلطة في الفناء الداخلي
and Xi Yan fought her way through them.
وشقّت شي يان طريقها عبرهم.
Her experience is similar to what you went through back then.
تجربتها مشابهة لما مررت به في ذلك الوقت.
The danger in the backyard now
الخطر في الفناء الخلفي الآن
is less than one in ten thousand of the arena.
أقل من واحد من كل عشرة آلاف في الساحة.
She has already taken the first step,
لقد خطت بالفعل الخطوة الأولى،
which shows she has some ability.
وهذا يدل على أنها تمتلك بعض القدرات.
If she can truly make the position of Madam vacant,
إذا استطاعت حقاً أن تجعل منصب السيدة شاغراً،
I might just look upon her with new eyes.
ربما أنظر إليها بعيون جديدة.
Your Lordship, something has happened!
يا صاحب السعادة، لقد حدث شيء ما!
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Young Lady.
يا آنسة.
You're here.
أنت هنا.
Useless!
عديم الفائدة!
You couldn't even manage a trivial thing like blinding Xi Yan.
لم تستطع حتى القيام بأمر تافه مثل إعماء شي يان.
You even caused Yu to be angry at me.
بل إنك تسببت في غضب يو مني.
Quickly dispose of her.
تخلص منها بسرعة.
Go.
يذهب.
Chunyun.
تشونيون.
Save me.
أنقذني.
After Young Lady saved my life,
بعد أن أنقذت الشابة حياتي،
I found a job
لقد وجدت وظيفة
at this teahouse.
في هذا المقهى.
I finally survived.
لقد نجوت أخيراً.
You mentioned in your letter
ذكرت في رسالتك
that you have news of Shen Yunqi and Lian.
أن لديك أخباراً عن شين يونكي وليان.
That day, the Princess gave the order,
في ذلك اليوم، أصدرت الأميرة الأمر،
and I had no choice but to sell them off.
ولم يكن أمامي خيار سوى بيعها.
A few days ago,
قبل بضعة أيام،
I found out about
لقد اكتشفت أمر
the bondswoman who sold them that day.
السيدة التي باعتهم في ذلك اليوم.
Where are they now?
أين هم الآن؟
I only found out about Lian's whereabouts.
لم أعرف سوى مكان وجود ليان.
She...
هي...
She was sold by the bondswoman to a man named Li Gang.
باعتها المرأة التي كانت تعولها لرجل يدعى لي غانغ.
Li Gang, the former steward of the Shen Residence?
لي غانغ، المشرف السابق على منزل شين؟
Where is he?
أين هو؟
The Eastern Suburb Residence.
مسكن الضواحي الشرقية.
(Shen Residence Steward, Li Gang)
(لي غانغ، مشرف الإقامة في شين)
I'll talk!
سأتحدث!
I was in the Shen family
كنتُ من عائلة شين
to search for the Shen family's treasure map.
للبحث عن خريطة كنز عائلة شين.
Treasure map?
خريطة كنز؟
It is rumored that the treasure in the map
يشاع أن الكنز الموجود في الخريطة
can...
يستطيع...
Can make a person richer than a nation.
يمكن أن يجعل الشخص أغنى من أمة بأكملها.
Your Lordship, someone infiltrated Li Gang's Residence.
يا صاحب السمو، لقد تسلل أحدهم إلى مقر إقامة لي غانغ.
Who?
من؟
Xi Yan.
شي يان.
(It's her again.)
(إنها هي مرة أخرى.)
Lian!
له!
(Shen Residence maid, Lian)
(ليان، خادمة منزل شين)
Li Gang is worse than an animal.
لي غانغ أسوأ من الحيوان.
Who are you?
من أنت؟
How do you know me?
كيف تعرفني؟
Come on.
تعال.
Don't say so much.
لا تتحدث كثيراً.
Follow me.
اتبعني.
The Shen family is gone.
لقد رحلت عائلة شين.
The Young Master is missing.
الشاب السيد مفقود.
Young Lady is dead too.
الشابة ماتت أيضاً.
I no longer have
لم يعد لدي
anywhere else to go.
إلى أي مكان آخر أذهب إليه.
I might as well die.
ربما من الأفضل لي أن أموت.
Lian.
ليان.
Lian,
ليان،
look at me.
انظر إليَّ.
I am Shen Changning.
أنا شين تشانغنينغ.
I am not dead.
أنا لست ميتاً.
No!
لا!
How could you be Young Lady?
كيف يمكنكِ أن تكوني آنسة؟
Listen to me.
استمع لي.
Lian,
ليان،
why don't you sit on the bed?
لماذا لا تجلس على السرير؟
My body is already soiled.
جسدي متسخ بالفعل.
I don't want to dirty Young Lady's bed anymore.
لا أريد أن أوسخ فراش الشابة بعد الآن.
Nonsense.
هراء.
Come.
يأتي.
What is purity,
ما هي الطهارة؟
and what is filth?
وما هو القذارة؟
Everything lies in the heart, not the body.
كل شيء يكمن في القلب، وليس في الجسد.
The one who is filthy is Li Gang, and those wearing human skin
الشخص القذر هو لي غانغ، وأولئك الذين يرتدون جلد الإنسان
but acting like beasts.
لكنهم يتصرفون كالوحوش.
The filthy ones are those who cannot tell right from wrong,
أما الأنجاس فهم الذين لا يستطيعون التمييز بين الصواب والخطأ.
who cannot reason,
من لا يستطيع التفكير المنطقي،
and throw all the dirt
وألقِ بكل الأوساخ
onto the victims.
ثم ننتقل إلى الضحايا.
It's alright.
لا بأس.
It's alright, Lian.
لا بأس يا ليان.
Everything is over.
انتهى كل شيء.
We still have each other,
ما زلنا نملك بعضنا البعض،
don't we?
أليس كذلك؟
Young Lady,
يا آنسة،
it was Lian's incompetence.
كان ذلك بسبب عدم كفاءة ليان.
The Young Master originally
السيد الشاب في الأصل
went with me to beg Li Wan'er for help,
رافقني ليتوسل إلى لي وان إير طلباً للمساعدة،
but I couldn't protect the Young Master.
لكنني لم أستطع حماية السيد الشاب.
When Li Wan'er sold him off,
عندما باعه لي وانير،
she knocked me unconscious.
لقد ضربتني حتى فقدت الوعي.
This is not your fault.
هذا ليس خطأك.
You should rest well first.
يجب أن ترتاح جيداً أولاً.
I will figure out a way to find my brother.
سأجد طريقة للعثور على أخي.
Young Lady,
يا آنسة،
that day, it was Pei Yu
في ذلك اليوم، كان باي يو
who personally sent master to prison.
الذي أرسل السيد إلى السجن شخصياً.
The Shen family's matter is inseparable from him.
إن مسألة عائلة شين لا تنفصل عنه.
How can Young Lady stay with the enemy?
كيف يمكن للسيدة الشابة أن تبقى مع العدو؟
I have my own plans.
لدي خططي الخاصة.
If...
لو...
If he knows you sheltered me,
إذا كان يعلم أنك آويتني،
won't he suspect your identity?
ألن يشك في هويتك؟
And how did Young Lady
وكيف فعلت الشابة
turn into Xi Yan?
هل يتحول إلى شي يان؟
Is it because of that past connection?
هل يعود ذلك إلى تلك العلاقة السابقة؟
(End of Episode)
(نهاية الحلقة)
You drink it.
تشربه.
Drink it and I'll tell you.
اشربه وسأخبرك.
I will make sure her soul is scattered and her spirit destroyed!
سأحرص على تشتيت روحها وتدمير عقلها!
♪Loneliness♪
♪الوحدة♪
♪How do I cross it?♪
♪كيف أعبرها؟♪
♪Whom have I ever failed?♪
♪من خذلتُ في حياتي؟♪
♪Incense burns through a few sticks,♪
♪يحترق البخور من خلال بضع أعواد،♪
♪Can the rest of my life be redeemed?♪
هل يمكن إصلاح ما تبقى من حياتي؟
♪The flowing years pass through desolation,♪
♪تمر السنين المتدفقة عبر الخراب،♪
♪Unwilling to forgive past mistakes,♪
♪غير راغب في مسامحة أخطاء الماضي،♪
♪Blaming myself for not protecting♪
ألوم نفسي لعدم حمايتي لنفسي.
♪Our vows as I should have.♪
♪عهودنا كما ينبغي لي أن أقولها.♪
♪Sorrow,♪
♪حزن،♪
♪Counting it carefully,♪
♪أحصيها بعناية،♪
♪Who stayed by my side through hardship?♪
♪من بقي بجانبي في الشدائد؟♪
♪There will eventually be a pure land,♪
♪ستكون هناك في النهاية أرض طاهرة،♪
♪Where all karmic burden is cast away.♪
♪حيث تُزال كل الأعباء الكارمية.♪
♪Not until worldly splendor fades,♪
♪لن يحدث ذلك إلا بعد أن يزول بريق الدنيا،♪
♪Can one understand what cuts to the bone.♪
هل يستطيع المرء أن يفهم ما يقطع العظم؟
♪At dusk, with white hair,♪
♪عند الغسق، بشعر أبيض،♪
♪I still cannot fathom destiny.♪
♪ما زلتُ عاجزاً عن فهم القدر.♪
♪After countless struggles across the waters,♪
♪بعد صراعات لا حصر لها عبر المياه،♪
♪At last the lotus heart awakens.♪
♪أخيرًا يستيقظ قلب اللوتس.♪
♪Drifting across three lifetimes,♪
♪انجراف عبر ثلاث حيوات،♪
♪Just to wait for your once-in-a-thousand-years glance.♪
♪فقط لننتظر نظرتك التي لا تتكرر إلا مرة كل ألف عام.♪
♪The distant mountains fade along the path home,♪
تتلاشى الجبال البعيدة على طول الطريق المؤدي إلى المنزل.
♪I walk with you through morning bells and evening drums.♪
أسير معك عبر أجراس الصباح وطبول المساء.
♪Our story lies in the mountains,♪
قصتنا تكمن في الجبال،
♪Like an ink-washed immortal painting.♪
♪كلوحة خالدة مغسولة بالحبر.♪
♪Where blossoms fall,♪
♪حيث تتساقط الأزهار♪
♪I'm glad the fragrance in our hearts stays the same.♪
♪يسعدني أن العطر في قلوبنا يبقى كما هو.♪
♪Youth slips away,♪
♪الشباب يتلاشى،♪
♪Just to wait for your once-in-a-thousand-years glance.♪
♪فقط لننتظر نظرتك التي لا تتكرر إلا مرة كل ألف عام.♪
♪Dreams wander back to the old road where we met,♪
♪تعود الأحلام إلى الطريق القديم حيث التقينا،♪
♪Watching you gently play the zither.♪
♪أشاهدك وأنت تعزف على آلة الزيثارة برفق.♪
♪Time rests upon the strings,♪
♪الزمن يستقر على الأوتار،♪
♪Waiting for someone to brew a pot of tea♪
♪أنتظر من يُعدّ لي إبريق شاي♪